Zara Teo Xiao Xuan

Networks Engineer, UX/UI Designer

CONTACT

zarateo@gmail.com

+65 8533-7364

0

174A Edgedale Plains, Singapore 821174

linkedin.com/in/zara-teo in

ABOUT

I am a highly motivated individual who never ceases to improve myself. I am a humble leader, have experience in leading people of different backgrounds and diversities and am passionate about learning more about Cybersecurity, UX/UI Design and Networks.

EDUCATION

DIPLOMA IN INFOCOMM AND SECURITY

Nanyang Polytechnic 2019 - 2022

'O' LEVELS

Zhonghua Secondary School 2014 - 2017

KEY SKILLS

Network Security

Network Architecture

Cybersecurity

Critical Thinking

Communication

Team leadership

CERTIFICATIONS

CCENT / 2019 / Cisco
CCNA / 2020 / Cisco
CCNP / 2021 / Cisco
OSCP / 2022 / Offensive Security

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INTERN

GovTech / Singapore / Mar 2021 – Sep 2021

- Troubleshooting TCP dumps and packet capture analysis
- Proactively monitor 200+ network devices and servers to detect and resolve issues before services are impacted
- Deploy and maintain firewalls from different vendors including next-generation firewalls and site-to-site VPNs
- Implemented SMNP solutions to monitor more than 113 network devices across 15 different locations

PART TIME STUDENT ASSISTANT

Nanyang Polytechnic / Singapore / 2019 - 2022

- Installation, engineering and maintenance of enterprise grade software and firewalls for more than 1000 small units and 20 main units
- Helped to manage a critical, business impact 24x7x365 large scale network
- Implemented next-generation network architectures
- Implement and maintain layer 2 and 3 services such as VLAN,
 STP and VTP
- Helped keep systems and server up to date

AWARDS

SEMI-FINALIST / 2016 / Julia Gabriel's Singapore Secondary School Debating Championships

BRONZE / 2019 / Cyber Defenders
Discovery Camp (CDDC)

DIRECTOR'S LIST / 2019 / Nanyang
Polytechnic

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Nanyang Scholarship Recipient (2019 - 2022)

Edusave EAGLES Award (2015)

Edusave Good Progress Award (2015)

Edusave EAGLES Award (2013)

Edusave Certificate of Academic Achievement (2011)

ONLINE PORTFOLIO

https://zaramichaela.github.io/

LEADERSHIP POSITIONS

VICE-PRESIDENT / PRESIDENT Zhonghua Secondary School / ELDDS / 2015 - 2017

- Schedule and coordinate meetings, appointments, and CCA sessions for all CCA members and Executive Committee members
- Wrote scripts for short plays and for our Singapore Youth Festival showcase
- Created various props and backdrops for different showcases
- Communicate with school leaders and CCA teachers on the CCA's progress and any issues or potential issues
- Manage travel and expense reports for department team members

HEAD OF PUBLICITY DEPARTMENT

Zhonghua Secondary School / Student Council / 2016 - 2017

- Take photographs for school events and showcases
- Organize Student Council camps, Publicity outings and bonding time
- Do content creation in the form of write-ups, photography editing and video editing

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

BEFRIENDER

Helping Joy / 2019 - Present

- Spend time with an elderly lady from Orange Valley Nursing Home
- Organize and plan various weekly outings for the elderly

TUTOR

St Peter's Church / 2018 - 2019

- Tutored less-privileged primary and secondary school students
- Helped out in a reading program for kids aged 2 to 12
- Coached and motivated students to aim high and do well in school